<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Karuppiah&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Karuppiah&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 19:40:35 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Writing a Blog</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/writing-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 19:40:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/writing-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>TLDR Just get started with that one line in your draft. Just write. Write as a habit! :)
Longer version Disclaimer - I have read very few things about writing blogs. I have written only a few blog posts and I&amp;rsquo;m not some famous blogger (yet? :P). These are just my thoughts / opinions. I have also heard a bit of recommendations and learned from others, so it&amp;rsquo;s also reiterating some of those recommendations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jabba: A Java Version Manager</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/jabba-a-java-version-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 15:02:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/jabba-a-java-version-manager/</guid>
      <description>TLDR; Try Jabba, an Open Source Tool for managing multiple Java versions in your system. It&amp;rsquo;s written in Golang. It has been inspired by nvm which manages Node versions
Video Version Before going into the post, if you prefer videos over blogs, you can checkout this YouTube video, which has the same information as this blog post.
  This blog post will be mostly the text version of the video :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validating Beans and Testing It</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/validating-beans-and-testing-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 14:45:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/validating-beans-and-testing-it/</guid>
      <description>In my current project, we work with Spring Boot. Recently, I was writing a Data Transfer Object (DTO) and we also had to add validations to the fields. Usually, while doing this, we also add tests to ensure that in the future we don&amp;rsquo;t remove or change the validations by mistake and instead it&amp;rsquo;s more intentional as we have to also change the tests.
Some more context - we are writing Web APIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawing Tools Part 1: Excalidraw</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/drawing-tools-part1-excalidraw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 14:23:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/drawing-tools-part1-excalidraw/</guid>
      <description>TLDR; Try Excalidraw an Open Source Online drawing tool which has enough features for most of your basic needs! It also supports live collaboration for people working remotely! :)
Video Version Before going into the post, if you prefer videos over blogs, you can checkout this YouTube video, which has the same information as this blog post.
  This blog post will be mostly the text version of the video :) There might be a thing or two extra in this blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Signatures</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/digital-signatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 20:21:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/digital-signatures/</guid>
      <description>If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what a digital signature is, in layman terms you may think of this, a photo of your physical signature
Photo by Lewis Keegan - Skillscouter.com on Unsplash May be you could say that&amp;rsquo;s true, but only if it&amp;rsquo;s layman slang. Officially, in computer science, the concept of digital signature has a different meaning.
It does denote someone&amp;rsquo;s or some entity&amp;rsquo;s signature, in a digital world. Yes. So, that&amp;rsquo;s not wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lint-staged: Lint Your Staged Files</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/lint-staged-lint-your-staged-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 09:11:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/lint-staged-lint-your-staged-files/</guid>
      <description>In my project, we use this tool called lint-staged which is pretty awesome! I wanted to write this blog post to talk a little bit about it and also mention some of the cool things I liked about it! :D
To start off, I work on a React project with Typescript. We need to ensure we follow some good practices as much as possible, so we use ESLint in our project We also use Prettier for formatting, so that our code looks neat and the same always no matter who worked on it, letting us read code in a consistent manner and not fight about formatting rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role Based Access Control</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/role-based-access-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 20:02:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/role-based-access-control/</guid>
      <description>Role Based Access Control, also known as RBAC is method to provide / restrict access to users in a software system. It&amp;rsquo;s something that comes up in the topic of Authorization.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already heard about Authentication and Authorization, it&amp;rsquo;s worth to check out both of them. The one liner is, Authentication is all about identifying the user, it answers the question &amp;ldquo;hey user, who are you? identify yourselves, and prove me who you tell you are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aim for HTTPS</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/aim-for-https/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 09:13:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/aim-for-https/</guid>
      <description>TLDR;  Be aware of the benefits of HTTPS. Always try to use HTTPS when using a website Always try to use HTTPS when building / developing a website, even if your site does not get any sensitive or confidential input from the user at all, or store or serve any user data.  Longer version If you have not heard of HTTPS before but have heard of HTTP, I would recommend reading about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing Demos in Style!</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/doing-demos-in-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 20:02:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/doing-demos-in-style/</guid>
      <description>TLDR; Record your demos and use recording to show the demo. Or at least use the recording as a backup, in case the actual demo goes wrong.
Longer version Have you ever had to do a demo to an audience? Say in a workshop to teach something, or in a talk / learning session, or to show your colleagues something cool, or just to your clients or customers in a professional setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Softwares: Hindering vs Enabling</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/softwares-hindering-vs-enabling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 22:29:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/softwares-hindering-vs-enabling/</guid>
      <description>TLDR; &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not built for this thing&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not supposed to be done this way&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;It has a bug. This is not expected!&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s too rigid, not flexible or configurable&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;It does not have the feature that you want&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;You are expecting it to do too much. It&amp;rsquo;s not supposed to be doing that much maybe&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Some evil corporation&amp;rsquo;s mission is to hinder you. Just kidding. Dig deep. Understand the core of the problem&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 20:36:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/education/</guid>
      <description>Recently, when I was online on LinkedIn, I noticed this simple post which said something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;In a world of Byjus and White Hat Jr, be someone&amp;rsquo;s Khan Academy and Code.org&amp;rdquo;
I think people within India might be able to relate to some parts of it. The post is related to paid coding courses. You must have seen the tons of comments on the post - many criticizing the companies behind these paid coding courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beauty</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/beauty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 13:44:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/beauty/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to be 25 this December. Having lived only around 25 years on this planet, I may have less experience compared to you, also adding to the fact that I consider myself very very ignorant when it comes to the matters of the world or as one calls it &amp;ldquo;current affairs&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;general knowledge&amp;rdquo;. Given this background about myself, I would like to have a take on the topic of &amp;ldquo;Beauty&amp;rdquo; in this post, probably a sensitive / controversial topic, but I&amp;rsquo;m okay with that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barriers to attending Events</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/barriers-to-attending-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 16:28:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/barriers-to-attending-events/</guid>
      <description>I have conducted very few public events and lots of internal (company) events related to knowledge sharing in tech space. In this post I want to talk about barriers for participants to attending public events.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with in-person events. I&amp;rsquo;ll take an example of a knowledge sharing event which is open for everyone and free too. Usually such events need some space for people come together, relax and sit, to listen to the speaker share their learnings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning CSS: A bumpy journey</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/learning-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 21:35:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/learning-css/</guid>
      <description>Recently I took up the task of implementing the login feature of our application. I took it up knowing I know nothing, so that I&amp;rsquo;ll learn it and do it and come out of it learning something new and with some knowledge on how things work.
I kind of knew that my implementation would involve Keycloak, a software we use for Authentication and Authorization feature in our app. But little did I realize that I would have to also work with CSS to customize the theme of our login page, instead of using the default theme of the super cool Keycloak default login page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to One Time Passwords (OTPs)</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/intro-one-time-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 21:02:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/intro-one-time-passwords/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m no security expert. The post is more from a techy user&amp;rsquo;s perspective, with little research.
 I&amp;rsquo;m usually always into guessing what goes on behind the scenes of some technology and then checking online more about it and then understanding how it&amp;rsquo;s actually done.
So, in this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about One Time Passwords (OTPs) and going to try to take a crack at how it is probably implemented behind the scenes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Keycloak</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/getting-started-with-keycloak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 08:05:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/getting-started-with-keycloak/</guid>
      <description>For me, usually the fastest way to getting started with any big software - server side software, with other components (backend, proxy etc) is using docker and/ docker-compose.
Keycloak&amp;rsquo;s basic setup would be a Keycloak server with a database. It supports many databases actually.
The quickest way to get started with Keycloak would be to run Keycloak with H2 database, like this using docker
$ docker run -d --name keycloak -p 8080:8080 -e KEYCLOAK_USER=admin -e KEYCLOAK_PASSWORD=admin jboss/keycloak It will take a few seconds or a minute to bootup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Keycloak, Open Source Identity and Access Management System</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/introduction-to-keycloak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 21:17:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/introduction-to-keycloak/</guid>
      <description>In my current project, there was a decision made to use Keycloak for Identity and Access Management (IAM). People said that &amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t need to write code to do authentication and authorization and reinvent the wheel, it&amp;rsquo;s already done by a lot of people. Keycloak is just really good, it just works, use it&amp;rdquo;.
Now, I am pretty new to almost every technology in the project. So I&amp;rsquo;m still learning a lot of things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using CI/CD Artifacts for Faster Docker Image Builds</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/using-ci-cd-artifacts-for-faster-docker-image-builds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 08:29:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/using-ci-cd-artifacts-for-faster-docker-image-builds/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: This blog post is very context specific, so please consider your application and it&amp;rsquo;s context, and accordingly see if you can use this strategy.
 Story and the Problem Recently in our project, we were writing a Dockerfile to build a Docker image for our React App. It didn&amp;rsquo;t have any server side to it, just a static app. We decided to serve the frontend files (HTML, CSS, Js) using Nginx web server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nginx as Gateway</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/nginx-as-gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 08:46:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/nginx-as-gateway/</guid>
      <description>In our project, we are building a web app, with backend. We use a separate service called Keycloak for Identity and Access Management.
Given we have all this, initially we were exposing these through the same URL but with different ports
 Port 80 for our web app Port 8080 for the backend Port 80890 for Keycloak  The user experience for the user accessing the web app looked something like this -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step CLI to decode JWT tokens</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/step-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 21:05:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/step-cli/</guid>
      <description>tldr; step GitHub repo - https://github.com/smallstep/cli
$ # Reading from keyboard / standard input after running command. $ # Run command and then paste the JWT token as input and press Enter. $ step crypto jwt inspect --insecure eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzdWIiOiIxMjM0NTY3ODkwIiwibmFtZSI6IkpvaG4gRG9lIiwiaWF0IjoxNTE2MjM5MDIyfQ.SflKxwRJSMeKKF2QT4fwpMeJf36POk6yJV_adQssw5c { &amp;#34;header&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;alg&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;HS256&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;typ&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;JWT&amp;#34; }, &amp;#34;payload&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;sub&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;1234567890&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;John Doe&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;iat&amp;#34;: 1516239022 }, &amp;#34;signature&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;SflKxwRJSMeKKF2QT4fwpMeJf36POk6yJV_adQssw5c&amp;#34; } $ # Reading from file $ cat jwt-token.txt | step crypto jwt inspect --insecure { &amp;#34;header&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;alg&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;HS256&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;typ&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;JWT&amp;#34; }, &amp;#34;payload&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;sub&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;1234567890&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;John Doe&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;iat&amp;#34;: 1516239022 }, &amp;#34;signature&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;SflKxwRJSMeKKF2QT4fwpMeJf36POk6yJV_adQssw5c&amp;#34; } $ # Reading from environment variables $ echo $JWT_TOKEN | step crypto jwt inspect --insecure { &amp;#34;header&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;alg&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;HS256&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;typ&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;JWT&amp;#34; }, &amp;#34;payload&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;sub&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;1234567890&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;John Doe&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;iat&amp;#34;: 1516239022 }, &amp;#34;signature&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;SflKxwRJSMeKKF2QT4fwpMeJf36POk6yJV_adQssw5c&amp;#34; } Recently I was trying to decode the information present in a JWT token to understand what&amp;rsquo;s the information in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BitBucket Cloud doesn&#39;t support Git commit signing?</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/bitbucket-cloud-no-git-commit-sign/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 21:17:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/bitbucket-cloud-no-git-commit-sign/</guid>
      <description>Really? I understand it&amp;rsquo;s a less used feature. I have not seen many people talk about it or use it, but hey, it&amp;rsquo;s an important security feature - as anyone can masquerade as someone else! I mean, ideally it won&amp;rsquo;t happen, in a company or organization where everyone is trusted. It&amp;rsquo;s still a good thing. Also, if some open source community is using it, it&amp;rsquo;s still good. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what&amp;rsquo;s the deal, but BitBucket Cloud doesn&amp;rsquo;t support Git commit signing as of this writing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Python and Data Analysis Journey</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/my-python-and-data-analysis-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 21:06:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/my-python-and-data-analysis-journey/</guid>
      <description>I recently found out about the She Loves Data (SLD) community through my amazing company. Apparently quite a few colleagues of mine are volunteering and helping the SLD community. There was this Introduction to Python workshop by SLD and I found out that they are looking for volunteers as there were a lot of registrations. I was encouraging some of my friends to volunteer and mentor in the workshop to help participants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Blog? Why Share Knowledge?</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/why-blog-why-share-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 19:57:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/why-blog-why-share-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m not some genius. The below are just my thoughts / opinions based on experience. I&amp;rsquo;m not basing it off of any facts really.
 I&amp;rsquo;ll be pretty straight forward on this. We live in a very crazy competitive world. Almost everything seems to be a race. Even if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to be in it, you are kind of in it, or at least affected by it. Atleast that&amp;rsquo;s my opinion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Profile Readme</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/github-profile-readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 16:48:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/github-profile-readme/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was lurking on the Internet. I stumbled upon this user profile on GitHub
https://github.com/GOVINDDIXIT
Govind&amp;rsquo;s profile looked so cool! Below is a screenshot of the same
That&amp;rsquo;s just a part of it! There was a lot of information in the profile. After seeing this, I was searching on the Internet to find some docs on how to do this. Weirdly I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any official GitHub docs on how to add readme to a user profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Childhood Crazy Tech Stuff</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/childhood-crazy-tech-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 20:49:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/childhood-crazy-tech-stuff/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t remember much now, but I&amp;rsquo;m gonna try to recall as much as possible. So, I was young, I don&amp;rsquo;t remember at what age this happened. Surely some age after I was 11 or 12 as that&amp;rsquo;s what I got my new computer and Internet. And I think at that time Orkut was pretty famous. So a bit later than that when Facebook was famous in India. So, I saw something about a different theme for Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Networking and Hacking</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/learning-networking-hacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 20:14:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/learning-networking-hacking/</guid>
      <description>This was during college. I was trying to learn hacking. Haha. I remember following this series of blog posts, which explained stuff. I even printed them out to read and understand and learn. These were big blog posts. The first few posts they mostly taught about networking, this is because, to hack someone, remotely, you need to access their system remotely, and remotely means there must be some connection to the system, and that&amp;rsquo;s where networks and network concepts came in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Chose Simplicity. I Chose Empathy</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/i-chose-simplicity-i-chose-empathy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 18:50:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/i-chose-simplicity-i-chose-empathy/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was writing this code for a JSON REST API. We were adding an extra field to our API structure, for a resource. For the sake of simplicity let&amp;rsquo;s assume we were building an API to store rich text in our database. The size of this rich text was small, like 500 characters, that&amp;rsquo;s it. And let&amp;rsquo;s say we came up with some simple solutions on how to store the rich text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s a Software?</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/what-is-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 18:31:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/what-is-software/</guid>
      <description>A software is more than just source code. This is true for anything. Any creation. The creation may be defined by people in just a few words, the reality is, there are always people behind the creation. There&amp;rsquo;s always a people aspect to things. In Software, this means everyone involved with the software - all of the teams of developers, product managers, quality analysts, project managers, and Every other than Role who helped build the software and is part of the company behind the software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obscure Javascript</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/obscure-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 18:20:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/obscure-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Many front end javascript files are bundled into one file usually, and all the spaces removed, all function and variable names changed - minified. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what else they do as part of &amp;ldquo;minification&amp;rdquo; process and bundling process. Finally you get that obscure JavaScript file. This also reduces the size of the file and hence the amount of data to be downloaded, which makes a big difference, especially for people with low network bandwidth or bad Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prettified JSON in HTTP Response</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/prettified-json-in-http-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 18:16:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/prettified-json-in-http-response/</guid>
      <description>I was randomly thinking about JSON, jq tool and the tool&amp;rsquo;s ability to prettify JSON by indenting with spaces and it&amp;rsquo;s ability to remove spaces too.
Suddenly for a second I was thinking why HTTP responses should not have spaces? If they had spaces they would look so cool right? 😂
In a moment I got the answer - yeah. You got it right. Prettifying the JSON with indentation will mean - add spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloning All Git Repos From GitLab Group</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/cloning-all-git-repos-from-gitlab-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 07:35:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/cloning-all-git-repos-from-gitlab-group/</guid>
      <description>tldr; $ curl -H &amp;quot;PRIVATE-TOKEN: $GITLAB_TOKEN&amp;quot; \ &amp;quot;https://&amp;lt;gitlab-url&amp;gt;/api/v4/groups/&amp;lt;group-id&amp;gt;/projects?per_page=100&amp;quot; | jq \ &#39;map({ id: .id, name: .name, ssh_url: .ssh_url_to_repo, http_url: .http_url_to_repo })&#39; $ cat projects.json | jq &amp;quot;.[].http_url&amp;quot; -r | xargs -I {} git clone {} $ # OR $ cat projects.json | jq &amp;quot;.[].ssh_url&amp;quot; -r | xargs -I {} git clone {} Longer version I have joined a new project. My use case was to clone all the repositories in our team&amp;rsquo;s GitLab group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pot</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/the-pot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 19:54:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/the-pot/</guid>
      <description>Found this on my Tumblr blog. Migrating it here
 Started off to write a poem. It turned out to be something else. :P
The Pot Everyone&amp;rsquo;s born with a pot.
A very special kind of pot,
which is very much connected
to you and has life in it.
When you are young,
it&amp;rsquo;s soft and big.
And it&amp;rsquo;s prone to breaking.
And breaks most times.
People always break it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Alone</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/walking-alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 19:47:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/walking-alone/</guid>
      <description>Found this on my Tumblr blog. Migrating it here
 A friend said, what I write comes under &amp;ldquo;freestyle poem&amp;rdquo; category&amp;hellip;This time, this one, comes under &amp;ldquo;freestyle essay&amp;rdquo; category I guess ;) :D
Walking Alone I don&amp;rsquo;t know when I
started walking alone.
I just know, I have
been doing it for a
long time since then.
Walking alone&amp;hellip; in many
places and stages of life.
And each time, it has</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow and Friendship</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/shadow-and-friendship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 19:39:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/shadow-and-friendship/</guid>
      <description>Found this on my Tumblr blog. Migrating it here
 This is a poem that I wrote long long ago, as far as I remember. Probably during 12th Std or may be during 1st sem college. My Google Drive details say I uploaded this poem in Dec 2013. Now, I am posting it here. Thank God I got this :P
Shadow and Friendship My shadow has always been a good companion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Friends and The Rose</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/my-friends-and-the-rose/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 19:19:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/my-friends-and-the-rose/</guid>
      <description>I was walking with my friends on the road. Suddenly I smelled a rose from the other side of the river. I didn&amp;rsquo;t inform my friends and sneaked out and left them to go in the opposite side towards the river.
The water was flowing happily fast. It was so hard for me to cross the river, but I crossed it. I ran towards the smell of the rose. I could finally see it from far away with lot of thorns around it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Imagine</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/i-imagine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 09:56:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/i-imagine/</guid>
      <description>This is a small writing
 I&amp;rsquo;m watching my series and some funny scenes come and I&amp;rsquo;m laughing and I imagine how it will be funny for you too
I imagine about how you would laugh at it if you had been sitting near me
I imagine how you would just slowly lean your head on my shoulders while laughing and then sit straight smiling
I imagine how your hair, eyes and smile would look</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dress</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/the-dress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 09:55:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/the-dress/</guid>
      <description>This is a small writing
 I go to her place imagining what she&amp;rsquo;s probably wearing
I see her waiting for me outside with the big basket of clothes
As I approach her, I see her. There she is. In pure white. And she isn&amp;rsquo;t smiling. I wonder why
I finally reach her. She hands the basket and gives me some shillings and then some extra and says &amp;ldquo;Just make sure it goes away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Cheatsheet for Commands and Stuff</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/my-cheatsheet-for-commands-and-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 12:49:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/my-cheatsheet-for-commands-and-stuff/</guid>
      <description>Recently I have been noting down the commands I use :P I think it&amp;rsquo;s especially useful for commands that take quite some time for me to get right and I&amp;rsquo;m always searching the Internet or the command manuals or help text for the same thing again and again each time. And the search sometimes takes time - almost the same amount of time that took for me during the first time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Is About People</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/code-is-about-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 08:48:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/code-is-about-people/</guid>
      <description>Actually, everything is about people. Including code. I remember reading about this in Twitter. Since then and up until now, I have seen multiple instances where I can clearly say everything is about people, including code. I mean, I guess we have made ourselves the centre of the Earth 😅 If we should be inclusive, I think the phrasing should be - everything is about living organisms. For this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll limit myself to talking about just code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>uff Tool</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/uff-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 08:03:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/uff-tool/</guid>
      <description>tldr Install uff and check it out! Below is an example!
$ go get -u -v github.com/karuppiah7890/uff $ git clone https://github.com/fishworks/fish-food $ cd fish-food $ uff Food/helm.lua 2.14.2 existing food version: 2.14.1 upgrading fish food Food/helm.lua to version 2.14.2 ... done! 🐠 GitHub repo for the plugin - https://github.com/karuppiah7890/uff
Longer version Sometime ago I created a tool called uff. The repo is here
In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell the story behind the tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Prometheus Operator, Prometheus, Alertmanager and Grafana</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/installing-prometheus-operator-prometheus-alertmanager-and-grafana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 19:31:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/installing-prometheus-operator-prometheus-alertmanager-and-grafana/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post I&amp;rsquo;m going to teach about how to install Prometheus Operator, Prometheus, Alertmanager and Grafana
If you want to checkout the video version of this blog which shows a demo, you can see the below video
  This blog post has written in response to a message here - https://lists.cncf.io/g/cncf-helm/message/293 . Usually I don&amp;rsquo;t like to give away answers easily, but sometimes it feels like - why do things have to be hard?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Blog? Why Open Source? Why Learning Log?</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/why-blog-why-open-source-why-learning-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 18:56:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/why-blog-why-open-source-why-learning-log/</guid>
      <description>Recently I wrote about how I write for myself and mostly because I forget stuff. I think I can find more reasons to write - the more, the better. It&amp;rsquo;ll make me write more! So, I remember reading this concept of Learning in Public, but I just remembered the phrase not the whole concept later, until recently when I read this post about learning in public - and few other posts related to it</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing to Open Source: Efforts and Rework</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/contributing-to-open-source-efforts-and-rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 16:24:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/contributing-to-open-source-efforts-and-rework/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, the craziest thing for me is - the amount of effort I put into something, some work, but how I do it all wrong because I don&amp;rsquo;t know some of the expectations of the work. It&amp;rsquo;s very crazy.
In terms of Open Source, it has happened quite a lot of times for me I think. I&amp;rsquo;ll be working on a Pull Request to fix an issue. I&amp;rsquo;ll take an approach and then maintainers feel that the approach can be changed totally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Dummy Files</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/creating-dummy-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 18:09:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/creating-dummy-files/</guid>
      <description>I have created dummy files two times or so now. Now, what do I mean when I say a dummy file? In my case, I mean a file which doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any actual content, instead it has more like some random dummy data. Similar to the lorem ipsum content that people use for placeholder text during development when they don&amp;rsquo;t have actual content ready yet
Before telling the reasons for why I needed a dummy file, I&amp;rsquo;ll first tell how I created a dummy file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VSCode Golang Programming</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/vscode-golang-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 14:10:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/vscode-golang-programming/</guid>
      <description>I usually use IntelliJ when I&amp;rsquo;m working on company projects. These days I have been trying to use VS Code. Recently I have realized that VS Code&amp;rsquo;s Golang extension has a lot of new features to offer. I think a lot of credit goes to gopls (&amp;ldquo;go please&amp;rdquo;) - https://github.com/golang/tools/tree/master/gopls . I have been using VS Code with repos that have go modules (without vendoring). With vendoring on and go v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Code Is Happiness</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/no-code-is-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 19:46:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/no-code-is-happiness/</guid>
      <description>Like, really, don&amp;rsquo;t you think no code is awesome? Kelsey Hightower created this repo - https://github.com/kelseyhightower/nocode where he says there&amp;rsquo;s no code, nothing to deploy, and that it is the best way to write secure and reliable applications
Wow right? :P I mean, if you are a software engineer, and you get paid for writing no code, that would be awesome right? 😂🤣 Well, not gonna happen I guess. You Will write code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Test Test Code</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/test-test-test-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 19:22:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/test-test-test-code/</guid>
      <description>I have contributed to a few open source repositories. One good thing I learned is - tests are very important and that we need to make sure that the software is robust. And when software breaks, it means that some test for a scenario is missing - add it, and the test will fail, as there&amp;rsquo;s a bug and then it can be fixed. Now, that&amp;rsquo;s a fix being done after the bug has been discovered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinning up VMs in my local</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/spinning-up-vms-in-my-local/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 08:42:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/spinning-up-vms-in-my-local/</guid>
      <description>This post is about how I spin up VMs in my local machine. This is considering I have already chosen to run something in a VM and not in a container like Docker container or any other tech like unikernels and others that I don&amp;rsquo;t know about :p
Now, back to VMs. Now, usually I used to use Virtual Box to run VMs in my local. It&amp;rsquo;s open source and I can run it in my Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Like to Write Things Down</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/i-like-to-write-things-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 08:52:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/i-like-to-write-things-down/</guid>
      <description>I consider myself a bit forgetful. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to tell the reasons for that, but I think I know some reasons 🤔 anyways, now, I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I can solve the problem and remember more things. And even if I do, it will take time and till then, I need some mechanism to help me remember things. So, what do I do? Other than my brain, what can store lots of information and not forget it very easily?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Cash and Digital Transactions</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/no-cash-and-digital-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 21:32:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/no-cash-and-digital-transactions/</guid>
      <description>So today I was planning to travel in a van to a metro station and then in metro, go to the metro station near my house and then walk to my house which is close by
Unfortunately my van didn&amp;rsquo;t come. I then walked to a bus station and got a bus to the metro station. Now I had to pay, in cash for the bus fare. And I realized that I might not have cash in my wallet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kubectl commands</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/kubectl-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 09:30:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/kubectl-commands/</guid>
      <description>Some of the commands that I use in my day to day work when interacting with kubernetes clusters
Exec / execute into a pod If you have kube-fzf, you can use execpod which is an interactive way to exec into a pod&amp;rsquo;s container
$ # exec into a pod in the default namespace $ execpod $ # exec into a pod in a particular namespace $ execpod -n &amp;lt;namespace-name&amp;gt; $ # exec into a pod in any namespace by seeing all namespace pods $ execpod -a Or if you don&amp;rsquo;t have kube-fzf, you can use the below</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSS Stories Part 1: Write Tests to Fix That Bug!</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/oss-stories-part-1-write-tests-to-fix-that-bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 15:10:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/oss-stories-part-1-write-tests-to-fix-that-bug/</guid>
      <description>I recently thought I should share some of my Open Source Stories! Stories about how I contributed, what happened, some learnings, swags and what not. Anything that happened with respect to Open Source for me. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll try to write as much stories as possible! Not all of them will have technical stuff. It&amp;rsquo;s a story :P It could have anything. So, today I have one story to tell ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>asciinema to record your terminal</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/asciinema-to-record-your-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 10:47:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/asciinema-to-record-your-terminal/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever tried to record your terminal? Or seen anyone&amp;rsquo;s recording of their terminal? Usually people record to show how a tool works and put it in the tool&amp;rsquo;s README in the git repo. You can also record to do tutorial videos and more :)
So, my first thought to record my terminal would have been to just record my screen or terminal window using some screen recording / screen capture tool like Kap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to Make My Life Easier While Coding</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/trying-to-make-my-life-easier-while-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 09:22:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/trying-to-make-my-life-easier-while-coding/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: These are just my thoughts. Or rants. :P
Every day I code. I face problems. Usually I get immersed in the problem. These days I try to be lazy. I try. I think of how to go past the problem, get rid of it, not face it in the future, make my life easier.
I also don&amp;rsquo;t like to sit idle, waiting for my tests and build. I have a macbook pro 2017 version and even that&amp;rsquo;s not enough sometimes 🙈 we really need to work on better software folks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running 🏃‍♂️🏃‍♀️ is Tough</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/running-is-tough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 09:15:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/running-is-tough/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve planned to run a bit. To practice for a marathon - 5km one. I have run crazily once for 7.5 km. Almost killed myself in the process 😂
Yesterday I ran okay. I ran twice yesterday. Both times quite slowly, atleast that&amp;rsquo;s what I believe. It looked like I was running very slowly. But you should have seen the amount of energy that I was spending to do that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tmate: Share Your Terminal!</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/tmate-share-your-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 14:20:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/tmate-share-your-terminal/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever done remote pair programming over the Internet? Or tried to share your screen over the Internet to show someone something on your screen? Using slack, team viewer, zoom, and what not. How was the experience?
Being a programmer, I&amp;rsquo;m sure a lot of you spend your time in the terminal, editor / IDE and the browser? And probably more! Like slack :P
Now, let&amp;rsquo;s say, I&amp;rsquo;m going to use slack / zoom to just do audio call over the Internet, or use something like Google Meet or even just a phone call using my mobile network or over the Internet using WhatsApp</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redis CLI lolwut Command</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/redis-cli-lolwut-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 11:16:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/redis-cli-lolwut-command/</guid>
      <description>So, today I found something funny and interesting. Someone in our slack #tech-reads channel shared a tech read by antirez, the creator of redis software. This is the link that they shared -
http://antirez.com/news/123
I immediately tried out the command in my terminal and it was cool! See the recording here -
 The commands used in the recording are below
$ redis-cli 127.0.0.1:6379&amp;gt; lolwut 127.0.0.1:6379&amp;gt; lolwut 10 1 4 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Go in Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/debugging-go-in-visual-studio-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 15:55:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/debugging-go-in-visual-studio-code/</guid>
      <description>Long ago, in one post I wrote about how to debug Go program in Intellij IDEA / Goland. I realized not everyone uses IDEA ecosystem though, as they are paid. You could check out the IDEA community edition though, which is free. And you can install the Go plugin from here. In my case I used to use IDEA Ultimate and evaluate it (Evaluator version) for free, now I use a company license.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mission Crusader 2020</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/mission-crusader-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 13:00:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/mission-crusader-2020/</guid>
      <description>A friend of mine recently shared some posters about a cyclathon / cycle rally
He knew that I have been cycling a bit recently. He asked if I wanted to come. I said okay and started planning for this event
The theme being &amp;ldquo;pedal to fight cancer&amp;rdquo;. The fund from the event would go to Cancer children at Adyar Cancer Institute in Chennai, where I live
The first thought was - it&amp;rsquo;s too early 😂 But I just registered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/cooking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 09:39:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/cooking/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been so cool to make my own breakfast. Like, some of it, if not all
Two things that I have tried recently - sandwiches and omelette wraps. 😂 This is my own recipe - so my version of how I made the food, and how I named it too 😛
Sandwich Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the sandwich
I got some veggies first - cucumber, carrot, tomato and some sprouts. I decided the sprouts will be like a side dish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/cycling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 13:28:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/cycling/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been cycling for about two weeks now
I use the smart bike app to get a rented cycle and I got a helmet for my saftey and I drive almost everyday in the morning and sometimes I have ridden in the evening too during weekends
So, why and how did I start doing this?
I think the first inspiration for me is my friend Nimalan. Who started cycling and putting posts about his trips and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In a Class</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/in-a-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 22:34:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/in-a-class/</guid>
      <description>This is a story by me :)
 We are in a grade 10 class in AllCool School. Students are studying chemistry and their professor has asked them to solve a problem
Aman has finished the problem and he is acting as though he&amp;rsquo;s not done and is pretending he&amp;rsquo;s thinking about the problem and is looking around to pretend he wants help. While looking around he is thinking &amp;ldquo;Damn, I wish I could keep looking at Rahul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different Ways to Contribute to Open Source</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/different-ways-to-contribute-to-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 17:40:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/different-ways-to-contribute-to-open-source/</guid>
      <description>This is not an exhaustive list
 Donate Money Write code - bug fixes, features, security issue fixes, performance improvements Write docs, Fix docs Simply use the software and provide UI/UX feedback and propose different UI/UX by filing an issue Report bugs that you notice while using the software Check existing bugs in issues and help by reproducing the issue if no one has confirmed that it&amp;rsquo;s an issue with the software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helm values schema gen Plugin</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/helm-values-schema-gen-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 17:31:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/helm-values-schema-gen-plugin/</guid>
      <description>tldr $ helm plugin install https://github.com/karuppiah7890/helm-schema-gen $ helm schem-gen &amp;lt;values-yaml-file&amp;gt; GitHub repo for the plugin - https://github.com/karuppiah7890/helm-schema-gen
Longer version Today I finally created a Helm plugin that I wanted to for so long. The repo is here
In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell the story behind the plugin. First the what, then the why, and a bit of how.
The What Recently, helm released their version 3 which was a big thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenFaaS with containerd Series Part 1</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/openfaas-containerd-series-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 19:49:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/openfaas-containerd-series-part1/</guid>
      <description>This is one of the posts in a series where I&amp;rsquo;m going to write about openfaas and containerd working together. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t tried openfaas before, it&amp;rsquo;s interesting, give it a try! This is one of the posts which you can use to try openfaas!
In this first post, I&amp;rsquo;ll just show you what I tried out recently. This is me showing you how to just run openfaas along with containerd in one VM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Conference Story</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/a-conference-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 14:03:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/a-conference-story/</guid>
      <description>Arvind is attending KubeCon for the first time. He&amp;rsquo;s on his own.
Arvind: Wow, this is all so grand! Let&amp;rsquo;s find a place to sit and enjoy the day and find new friends maybe!
Arvind finds his place. He finds himself surrounded by a lot of people.
There&amp;rsquo;s a constant buzz around him. People talking about life and work.
The Conference starts with the keynote and the talks follow.
After some talks, it&amp;rsquo;s break time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Go in Intellij IDEA / GoLand</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/debugging-go-in-intellij-idea-or-goland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 07:56:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/debugging-go-in-intellij-idea-or-goland/</guid>
      <description>Recently me and a friend were trying to debug a stackoverflow error in helm. We used a lot of print statements in the code and were reading the code and seeing the flow and checking where it just blew up. At some point I realized we were putting lot of print statements and it was just becoming tedious to follow along the big code - it was some parsing code 😓 to parse the command line values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helm 3 Charts and OCI registries</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/helm-3-charts-and-oci-registries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/helm-3-charts-and-oci-registries/</guid>
      <description>Recently Helm 3 alpha version was released https://github.com/helm/helm/releases/tag/v3.0.0-alpha.1 🎉. There are lot of new things in this release, I wanted to write about one of these things - Pushing Charts to OCI Registries!
With helm 3, you can push your charts to container registries similar to pushing container images! TLDR; Show me your terminal!
 The commands being used in the video:
$ docker run -dp 5000:5000 --restart=always --name registry registry $ helm create my-chart $ ls $ helm chart save my-chart localhost:5000/my-chart:0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Open Source Journey</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/my-open-source-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 12:44:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/my-open-source-journey/</guid>
      <description>I think the first time I heard the term &amp;ldquo;Open Source&amp;rdquo; was when we were taught about different kinds of software in 12th grade. I still remember how we had so many defintions to remember, for terms like - proprietary, freeware, shareware, open source software. I&amp;rsquo;m able to recall only these terms. Also, the definitions had some similarities and I also remember getting confused about the differences and similarities between the terms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post!</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 21:13:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Now that you are reading this post, it means I finally created another blog and hosted it too 😛 Yay! 🎉
My previous blogs that I hosted using Blogger during college -
https://semlabs.blogspot.com/
https://semlectures.blogspot.com/
And now I have created this blog. I use these to create and host it:
 Hugo static site generator GitHub Pages Visual Studio Code Editor Markdown Emoji to put the awesome emojis in markdown 😁  Hoping to write tons of posts 😉 Stay tuned!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
