<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Karuppiah&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Karuppiah&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 17:40:02 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Different Ways to Contribute to Open Source</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/different-ways-to-contribute-to-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 17:40:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/different-ways-to-contribute-to-open-source/</guid>
      <description>This is not an exhaustive list
 Donate Money Write code - bug fixes, features, security issue fixes, performance improvements Write docs, Fix docs Simply use the software and provide UI/UX feedback and propose different UI/UX by filing an issue Report bugs that you notice while using the software Check existing bugs in issues and help by reproducing the issue if no one has confirmed that it&#39;s an issue with the software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helm values schema gen Plugin</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/helm-values-schema-gen-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 17:31:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/helm-values-schema-gen-plugin/</guid>
      <description>tldr $ helm plugin install https://github.com/karuppiah7890/helm-schema-gen $ helm schem-gen &amp;lt;values-yaml-file&amp;gt; GitHub repo for the plugin - https://github.com/karuppiah7890/helm-schema-gen
Longer version Today I finally created a Helm plugin that I wanted to for so long. The repo is here
In this post I&#39;m going to tell the story behind the plugin. First the what, then the why, and a bit of how.
The What Recently, helm released their version 3 which was a big thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenFaaS with containerd Series Part 1</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/openfaas-containerd-series-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 19:49:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/openfaas-containerd-series-part1/</guid>
      <description>This is one of the posts in a series where I&#39;m going to write about openfaas and containerd working together. If you haven&#39;t tried openfaas before, it&#39;s interesting, give it a try! This is one of the posts which you can use to try openfaas!
In this first post, I&#39;ll just show you what I tried out recently. This is me showing you how to just run openfaas along with containerd in one VM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Conference Story</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/a-conference-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 14:03:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/a-conference-story/</guid>
      <description>Arvind is attending KubeCon for the first time. He&#39;s on his own.
Arvind: Wow, this is all so grand! Let&#39;s find a place to sit and enjoy the day and find new friends maybe!
Arvind finds his place. He finds himself surrounded by a lot of people.
There&#39;s a constant buzz around him. People talking about life and work.
The Conference starts with the keynote and the talks follow.
After some talks, it&#39;s break time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Go in Intellij IDEA / GoLand</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/debugging-go-in-intellij-idea-or-goland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 07:56:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/debugging-go-in-intellij-idea-or-goland/</guid>
      <description>Recently me and a friend were trying to debug a stackoverflow error in helm. We used a lot of print statements in the code and were reading the code and seeing the flow and checking where it just blew up. At some point I realized we were putting lot of print statements and it was just becoming tedious to follow along the big code - it was some parsing code 😓 to parse the command line values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helm 3 Charts and OCI registries</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/helm-3-charts-and-oci-registries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/helm-3-charts-and-oci-registries/</guid>
      <description>Recently Helm 3 alpha version was released https://github.com/helm/helm/releases/tag/v3.0.0-alpha.1 🎉. There are lot of new things in this release, I wanted to write about one of these things - Pushing Charts to OCI Registries!
With helm 3, you can push your charts to container registries similar to pushing container images! TLDR; Show me your terminal!
 The commands being used in the video:
$ docker run -dp 5000:5000 --restart=always --name registry registry $ helm create my-chart $ ls $ helm chart save my-chart localhost:5000/my-chart:0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Open Source Journey</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/my-open-source-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 12:44:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/my-open-source-journey/</guid>
      <description>I think the first time I heard the term &amp;ldquo;Open Source&amp;rdquo; was when we were taught about different kinds of software in 12th grade. I still remember how we had so many defintions to remember, for terms like - proprietary, freeware, shareware, open source software. I&#39;m able to recall only these terms. Also, the definitions had some similarities and I also remember getting confused about the differences and similarities between the terms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post!</title>
      <link>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 21:13:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://karuppiah7890.github.io/blog/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Now that you are reading this post, it means I finally created another blog and hosted it too 😛 Yay! 🎉
My previous blogs that I hosted using Blogger during college -
https://semlabs.blogspot.com/
https://semlectures.blogspot.com/
And now I have created this blog. I use these to create and host it:
 Hugo static site generator GitHub Pages Visual Studio Code Editor Markdown Emoji to put the awesome emojis in markdown 😁  Hoping to write tons of posts 😉 Stay tuned!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>